# JESSIE BOUDREAU

POWER & ENERGY ENGINEER

226-581-0214



Jessie.boudreau@live.ca



/in/jessie-boudreau-46203ba5



www.jessieboudreau.com



Hamilton, ON L8L1W9



#### EDUCATION

# BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY - POWER & ENERGY

McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario 2017-2020

# ADVANCED DIPLOMA – ENERGY SYSTEMS ENGINEERING TECHNOLOGY

Conestoga College ITAL, Cambridge, Ontario 2013-2017

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

#### **MASTERCRAFT AWARD**

Conestoga College, 2017

Awarded for the best overall engineering capstone project.

#### INTERESTS

- Rock Climbing
- Martial Arts
- Camping & Hiking
- Reading
- Hacking

### PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Experienced Engineering Team Manager with a demonstrated history of working in the automotive industry and power industries. Skilled in Electrical Engineering, Leadership, Test Automation and Manufacturing Design. Fluent in English with professional working proficiency in French. Strong engineering professional working towards a Bachelor of Technology – B.Tech focused in Power & Energy Engineering from McMaster University.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **TEAM CAPTAIN**

MAC Formula Electric, McMaster University, September 2017 - Present

Chief engineer and project manager responsible for the MAC Formula Electric racing team. Lead development of the in-house designed accumulator and all subsequent systems necessary for delivering and controlling power to the four in-hub motors.

- Helped in development of the high voltage battery, PCB design with Altium, ECU software, state of charge and torque vectoring systems
- Developed wiring assembly and schematic drawings and aided with harness manufacturing
- Introduced new project management mechanisms to improve team productivity
- Procured cash and product sponsorships from companies operating locally and internationally

#### **ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING TECHNOLOGIST**

Erwin Hymer Group North America, Cambridge, July 2017 – August 2018

Principal electrical designer in multiple product development projects, including the Hymer Touring trailer and Roadtrek Transit Class B motorhome.

- Developed system schematics and wire harness drawings
- Coordinated with manufacturers to integrate subsystems into the primary coach control system
- Developed and executed test procedures for various research and development projects such as the in-house designed lithium batteries and autonomous driving controls

# **SOLAR TECHNICIAN CO-OP**

Merlyn Power Inc., Kitchener, May 2016 - August 2016

Solar system technician responsible for project acquisition, management and construction of solar photovoltaic and thermal systems

- Designed, installed and commissioned residential and commercial solar systems
- Performed liaison work between contractors, consultants, suppliers and project stakeholders
- Provided troubleshooting and technical support to ongoing projects